Heather Samsel

Email: hsshop1@gmail.com | Phone: 215-493-3869 | Yardley, PA 19067

Github: https://github.com/savycodr | LinkedIn: https://github.com/savycodr | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/heather-samsel

Website: https://savycodr.github.io/personal-portfolio

PROFESSIONAL TITLE

Full Stack Web Developer with background in architecture, engineering, and software development. Able to build sophisticated websites with full database backend from mockup to rollout. Continually increasing knowledge and experience by keeping abreast of evolving trends, techniques, and technologies to improve efficiency. Adept at working with diverse teams to implement projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, UML, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Firebase, SQL,

Node, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars, Socket.io, Passport

Applications: Github, MySQL, Heroku, Postman, Zoom, Linter, Mocha, Chai

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania

expected July 2019

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development,

Philadelphia, PA

Intensive 24-week boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications.

Washington University

2000

Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering

St. Louis, MO

Parks College of St. Louis University

1993

Bachelor of Science, Aerospace Engineering

St. Louis, MO

St. Louis University

1993

Bachelor of Arts, Physics

St. Louis, MO

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

2000- 2002

OpenText (formerly Hummingbird Communications)

Tallahassee, FL

Designed, coded, and tested commercial Java software for document control and storage.

- Introduced and directed UML for projects
- Created architecture for testing, revision control, and builds

Senior Analyst 1999-2000

Wells Fargo Advisors (formerly A. G. Edwards)

St. Louis, MO

Java mentor and technical lead for web based financial software. Consultant for integration with the enterprise infrastructure. Led projects; created schedules for iterative development. Designed and implemented coding and architectural standards. Wrote proofs of concept, collaborated with business users to create software specifications. Communicated design to developers using UML.

Senior Engineer 1996-1999

The Boeing Company

St. Louis, MO

Developed architecture to connect Java client interfaces with legacy software. Wrote code for application running structural analysis on virtual aircraft designs.

 Selected to represent Boeing on structural engineering team sent to Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Engineer, Advanced Design

1993-1996

Lockheed Martin Aeronautical Systems

St. Louis, MO

Developed software used for conceptualizing 3-D aircraft designs and analyzing capabilities. Wrote and presented aircraft design reviews to senior leadership. Created software to aid in the wiring design of the F-22 Raptor and the C-130J Hercules.

- Selected for the F-35 Joint Strike Fighter design team
- Aircraft designs were published in Aviation Week and Space Technology

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Vice President 2018-present

Makefield Women's Association

Lower Makefield, PA

Coordinate volunteer services at the homeless shelter. Raise funds for beneficiaries. Set and approve budget as a member of the finance committee.

Member since 2015

PROJECTS

Forum Furniture Store | <u>Link to Github</u> | <u>Link to deployed site</u> Developer

Full Stack Furniture Store that customizes for a user's style. Chat capability.

 Languages and technologies used: Javascript, JQuery, Sequelize, Handlebars, Sockets.io, Passport, Materialize

Burger Restaurant Full Stack App | <u>Link to Github</u> | <u>Link to deployed site</u> Developer

Full Stack Burger Creation app. Deployed to Heroku. Persists to MySQL database.

• Languages and technologies used: Javascript, JQuery, Sequelize, Handlebars, Bootstrap